Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going shopping for something.
我是Catherine，今天我们要去买点东西。
What are we going shopping for, Marco?
Marco，我们要去买什么？
That's right.
没错。
Today we are buying pants and we're going to try to see if we find a good pair of jeans.
今天我们要买裤子，看看能不能找到一条合适的牛仔裤。
Yeah, sometimes pants are too small, sometimes they're too big.
是啊，有时候裤子太小，有时候又太大。
Let's try and find the right pair today.
今天我们就试着找一条合适的。
Excuse me, can I try on this pair of jeans?
打扰一下，我能试穿这条牛仔裤吗？
Sure, let me see.
当然，让我看看。
I'm afraid we don't have any size 8's left.
恐怕我们没有8码的了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I'm always a size 4.
我一直穿4码。
Here, I'll try these.
来，我试试这条。
They seem a bit too tight.
这条好像有点紧。
Shall I find you a larger size?
需要我给您找大一号的吗？
No, they fit fine.
不，挺合身的。
They show off my curves perfectly.
完美地凸显了我的曲线。
Yeah, your love handles.
是啊，你的游泳圈。
They sure do, although here, you forgot to close this button.
确实凸显了，不过这里，你忘了扣这个扣子。
Yeah, right.
嗯，对。
I'll do it now.
我现在就扣上。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now, let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
现在，让我们看看“语言小贴士”里的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
All right, so today on Language Takeaway, the first phrase we have is actually a verbal
好的，今天在“语言小贴士”里，我们第一个短语实际上是一个动词
phrase.
短语。
This is what we do when we go to find some clothes.
这就是我们去买衣服时会做的事情。
We try on those clothes.
我们试穿那些衣服。
That's right.
没错。
So, this is, as you said, a verbal phrase and to try on a pair of pants or to try on
所以，就像你说的，这是一个动词短语，试穿一条裤子或
some clothes is to put them on and see if they are okay, if they're the right size.
试穿一些衣服，就是穿上它们看看是否合适，尺码对不对。
That's right.
没错。
So, if I'm in the store and I see a shirt that I really like, I go to the dressing room
所以，如果我在店里看到一件我非常喜欢的衬衫，我会去试衣间
to try it on.
试穿它。
Or you could say, oh my gosh, Marco, come here.
或者你可以说，哦天哪，Marco，过来。
This shirt is great.
这件衬衫太棒了。
You should try it on.
你应该试穿一下。
That's right.
没错。
So, you try it on or you try on something.
所以，你可以说try it on或者try on something。
All right.
好的。
So, as we said, we wanted to try on a pair of jeans.
所以，就像我们说的，我们想试穿一条牛仔裤。
So, let's take a look at this connection of words, pair of jeans.
那么，我们来看看这个词语搭配，pair of jeans。
All right.
好的。
So, you don't have a jeans.
所以，你不能说a jeans。
You have a pair of them.
你要说a pair of them。
And this is because you have not one but two legs.
这是因为你有一条腿，而是两条腿。
So, pair means two of something.
所以，pair表示两个东西。
That's right.
没错。
So, it doesn't mean that you have two pants, right?
所以，这并不意味着你有两条裤子，对吧？
It doesn't mean that you have two pieces of clothing.
并不意味着你有两件衣服。
It means that you have one piece of clothing that's a pair of jeans.
它意味着你有一件衣服，是一条牛仔裤。
That's right.
没错。
So, you have one part for one leg and one part for another leg.
所以，你有一条腿的部分和另一条腿的部分。
The same is true of glasses because glasses are for your two eyes.
眼镜也是一样，因为眼镜是给你的两只眼睛用的。
That's right.
没错。
So, you have a pair of glasses.
所以，你有一副眼镜。
That's right.
没错。
A pair of glasses, a pair of shoes.
一副眼镜，一双鞋。
Also.
也是。
Okay.
好的。
So, we are trying on these pair of jeans but they seem to be a bit too tight.
所以，我们正在试穿这条牛仔裤，但它们似乎有点太紧了。
All right.
好的。
So, tight is a word we use when something is too small.
所以，tight这个词用来形容某物太小。
It's hard to move if something is too tight.
如果某物太紧，就很难活动。
So, maybe if the pants are too small, they might be too tight.
所以，如果裤子太小，它们可能会太紧。
Yeah.
是的。
And we often say this especially to girls.
我们经常对女孩这么说。
My mom used to say this, oh no, you're not wearing that skirt.
我妈妈以前常说，哦不，你不能穿那条裙子。
It's too tight.
太紧了。
You can see your body underneath.
都能看到你的身体轮廓了。
Okay.
好的。
So, actually the opposite would be loose if something is too big.
所以，实际上相反的是loose，如果某物太大。
Too big.
太大。
If it's too big, it's loose.
如果太大，就是宽松的。
If it's too small, it's tight.
如果太小，就是紧的。
Okay.
好的。
Now, if it's not too big and not too small, then that means it fits.
现在，如果既不太大也不太小，那就意味着它合身。
It fits.
合身。
That's right.
没错。
So, I could say, I think I want to buy this pair of jeans.
所以，我可以说，我想买这条牛仔裤。
It fits very well.
它非常合身。
So, if the pants or the pair of jeans fit, it means they are okay for you.
所以，如果裤子或牛仔裤合身，意味着它们对你来说合适。
They're not too big, not too small.
它们不太大，也不太小。
They're comfortable.
它们很舒服。
Comfortable.
舒服。
And in this case, she said that they fit perfectly because they show off her curves.
在这个例子中，她说它们非常合身，因为它们凸显了她的曲线。
Now, what is she talking about my curves?
现在，她说的“我的曲线”是什么意思？
Well, a curve is something that's not straight.
嗯，曲线是指不直的东西。
It bends.
它会弯曲。
When we're talking about a person's curves, we're talking about maybe a woman's hips or
当我们谈论一个人的曲线时，我们可能指的是女性的臀部或
her behind, her rear end or her chest.
她的屁股、后部或胸部。
And so, women who have curves maybe are rounder, not flat.
所以，有曲线的女性可能更圆润，而不是扁平。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's something that usually you would use with girls, right?
所以，这通常用于形容女孩，对吧？
A girl has nice curves.
一个女孩有漂亮的曲线。
You wouldn't really say that for a guy, I think.
我想你不会这样形容一个男人。
No, guys, you don't really talk about curves.
不，对于男人，你不会谈论曲线。
But with girls, usually you can see someone's curves if she wears tight clothes.
但对于女孩，如果她穿紧身衣服，通常可以看到她的曲线。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, why don't we take a break?
那么，我们休息一下怎么样？
Let's review all this vocab and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
让我们复习一下这些词汇，稍后回来进行流利度训练。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Can I borrow this pair of jeans?
我能借这条牛仔裤吗？
Sure.
当然。
Let me see.
让我看看。
I'm afraid we don't have any size 8s left.
恐怕我们没有8号尺码了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I'm always a size 4.
我一直穿4号尺码。
Here, I'll try these.
这里，我试试这条。
They seem a bit too tight.
它们似乎有点太紧了。
Can I find you a larger size?
我能给你找大一号的吗？
No, they fit fine.
不，它们很合身。
They show off my curves perfectly.
它们完美地凸显了我的曲线。
Yeah, your love handles.
是啊，你的游泳圈。
They sure do.
确实如此。
Although, here, you forgot to close this button.
不过，这里，你忘了扣这个扣子。
Yeah, right.
是啊，没错。
I'll do it now.
我现在就扣上。
All right.
好的。
Now it's time for three phrases.
现在是三个短语的时间。
Let's take a look at those on Fluency Builder.
让我们看看流利度训练中的那些。
All right.
好的。
So we heard this phrase here, I'm afraid, and it means something maybe different from
所以我们听到了这个短语“I'm afraid”，它的意思可能和你以前听到的
what you've heard before.
有所不同。
So the shopkeeper said, I'm afraid we don't have any size 8s left.
店主说：“恐怕我们没有8号尺码了。”
That's right.
没错。
So, when you start a sentence like this, you're basically apologizing a little bit, right?
所以，当你这样开始一个句子时，你基本上是在表示一点歉意，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
It's like saying, I'm sorry, I don't think we have size 8s left.
这就像说：“对不起，我想我们没有8号尺码了。”
So maybe I go into the store and I say, well, I would like some chocolate milk, please.
所以也许我走进商店说：“嗯，我想要一些巧克力牛奶。”
And I say, I'm sorry, I'm afraid we ran out of chocolate milk.
然后我说：“对不起，恐怕我们的巧克力牛奶卖完了。”
I'm afraid we ran out.
恐怕我们卖完了。
So this means it's too bad or unfortunately, we don't have any.
所以这意味着太糟糕了，或者不幸的是，我们没有。
That's right.
没错。
So it's not the same being afraid like you're being, you're scared.
所以这和害怕不一样，不是那种恐惧。
No, it's not that afraid.
不，不是那种害怕。
It's a polite way for usually a shopkeeper to say, I'm sorry, we can't help you.
这是一种礼貌的方式，通常是店主说：“对不起，我们帮不了你。”
Okay.
好的。
So coming back to curves, the girl used this interesting phrasal verb there, to show off.
所以回到曲线，那个女孩用了一个有趣的短语动词“to show off”。
All right.
好的。
So we know the word to show, but to show something off, to show off means to display or exhibit.
所以我们知道“show”这个词，但“show something off”或“show off”意思是展示或炫耀。
It's almost like you want other people to look at you.
这几乎就像你想让别人看你。
Okay.
好的。
So if, I guess maybe you can see it on the street, if someone is in their car and they're
所以，我想你可以在街上看到，如果有人坐在车里，
playing loud music, kind of drawing attention to their car, they're kind of showing off
大声播放音乐，吸引别人注意他们的车，他们就是在炫耀
their car.
他们的车。
They want you to see their car or just hear how great sound system they have.
他们想让你看到他们的车，或者听到他们有多好的音响系统。
That's right.
没错。
Or some women will wear very, very short skirts because they want to show off their long legs.
或者有些女性会穿非常短的裙子，因为她们想炫耀自己的长腿。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
But now something that you don't really want to show off are your love handles.
但有些东西你不想炫耀，那就是你的游泳圈。
All right.
好的。
Now this is a very funny phrase.
这是一个非常有趣的短语。
It's actually something we say in spoken English that if you say it to someone else, it might
实际上，这是我们在口语英语中说的，如果你对别人说，可能会
be very rude.
非常无礼。
Love handles are the part of your body above your waist that if you have a little fat,
游泳圈是指你腰部以上，如果有一点脂肪，
it's like they're squishy.
就像软软的部分。
You can touch them.
你可以摸它们。
Right.
好的。
So just think about how maybe people that are a little bit overweight, they put on a
所以想想看，那些稍微有点超重的人，他们穿上
pair of pants and on their sides, in their waist, the extra skin that kind of is around
裤子的两侧和腰部，那些多余的赘肉。
the pants, that's called love handles.
这条裤子，那叫“爱的把手”（指腰部赘肉）。
And we say love handles because when someone hugs you or they want to hold you, that's
我们说“爱的把手”是因为当有人拥抱你或想搂住你时，那就是他们放手的部位。
where they put their hands.
他们把手放在哪里。
There's extra to hold on to.
有额外的部分可以抓住。
Right.
好的。
I think sometimes they may be called like tires or something like this.
我想有时候它们可能被叫做轮胎之类的东西。
Well, spare tire is in the front.
嗯，备胎在前面。
It's near your belly.
就在你肚子附近。
All right.
好的。
So that's called a spare tire.
所以那叫做备胎。
That's right.
没错。
So a spare tire is in the front.
所以备胎是在前面。
It's a belly.
这是一个肚子。
Normally, when people drink a lot of beer, very often they have a spare tire.
通常，当人们喝很多啤酒时，他们常常会有个啤酒肚。
But this is actually love handles are on the sides.
但这其实是腰间的赘肉。
But that's our last word today.
但这是我们今天的最后一个词了。
Let's remember that it's not something you want to go around telling people they have,
要记住，这不是你到处跟别人说他们有的东西，
but you can joke with your friends about it.
但你可以跟朋友开玩笑说这个。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
So let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
那我们最后再听一遍对话。
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Can I try on this pair of jeans?
我能试穿这条牛仔裤吗？
Sure.
当然。
Let me see.
让我看看。
I'm afraid we don't have any size eights left.
恐怕我们没有8码的了。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I'm always a size four.
我一直穿4码。
Here, I'll try these.
来，我试试这条。
They seem a bit too tight.
它们看起来有点太紧了。
Can I find you a larger size?
需要我帮你找大一号的吗？
No, they fit fine.
不，它们很合身。
They show off my curves perfectly.
它们完美地凸显了我的曲线。
Yeah, your love handles.
是啊，你的游泳圈。
They sure do.
确实凸显了。
Although here, you forgot to close this button.
不过这里，你忘了扣上这个扣子。
Yeah, right.
嗯，对。
I'll do it now.
我现在就弄。
All right.
好的。
So speaking about pants, I've noticed something that the girl asked for a size four, but she
说到裤子，我注意到那个女孩要的是四号，但她
really was a size eight.
其实穿八号。
So how does this work?
这到底是怎么回事？
Because as guys, we don't have size fours, five or ones or anything.
因为作为男人，我们没有四号、五号或一号之类的。
You buy a pair of jeans, you say size 32 in the waist and size 30 in length or something
你买条牛仔裤，会说腰围32、裤长30之类的
like this.
这样。
So that's right.
没错。
Men's clothes usually indicate the size of your waist.
男装通常标明腰围尺寸。
So 32 is a 32 inch waist.
所以32就是32英寸的腰围。
But women's clothes don't have those measurements.
但女装没有这些测量数据。
And I sometimes think it would be better if we did, because it's very hard.
我有时觉得要是也有就好了，因为很难搞。
Some stores have size four, which is one size, but if you go to another store, it's very
有些店有四号，是一个尺寸，但你去另一家店，就
different.
完全不一样。
So you always have to try on these clothes.
所以你总得试穿这些衣服。
But normally in America, the sizes go from zero, which is the very, very smallest to
但在美国，通常尺码从零号开始，这是最小最小的，到
14 or 16, which is the largest.
14或16号，这是最大的。
Normal size for most women would be an eight, I think, an eight or a 10.
对大多数女性来说，正常尺码大概是8号，我觉得，8号或10号。
And now obviously this depends on the countries, because like for example, being in Asia, in
当然这取决于国家，因为比如在亚洲，
China, the women are usually a little bit thinner or smaller.
在中国，女性通常更瘦小一些。
So it's harder, I think, for, it's harder to actually have this universal form of measurements
所以我觉得，很难有一个全球通用的尺码标准
for girls.
适用于女性。
That's right.
没错。
So in the back of your pants, for example, there'll usually be some fabric and it will
比如在裤子后面，通常会有块布料，上面会
say the size according to different countries.
标注不同国家的尺码。
So in America, size six, in China, size, I don't know, 28.
所以在美国是6号，在中国，我不知道，可能是28号。
And so they'll have the different numbers.
所以它们会有不同的数字。
And UK is also a different size.
英国也是不同的尺码。
Kind of like your shoes.
有点像鞋子。
If you look inside your shoe, it'll say, I think, a Japanese size, the UK size, which
如果你看鞋子里面，它会标有，我想，日本尺码、英国尺码，
is like 41, 42, and the USA size, which is like size eight or nine.
比如41、42，还有美国尺码，比如8号或9号。
So, it's very, very interesting, especially when you're buying clothes, you have to remember
所以，这非常非常有趣，尤其是买衣服时，你得记住
what size you are and you have to ask the person to, that you try it on.
自己的尺码，还得请人帮忙试穿。
Because some things I know you can't try on, right?
因为有些东西我知道你不能试穿，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And in some stores, you have to ask for help to take things off the racks.
而且在一些店里，你得请人帮忙从货架上拿东西。
So it can be very difficult.
所以可能会很麻烦。
But normally, if you say, hey, can I try this on, the shopkeeper will help you.
但通常，如果你说“嘿，我能试穿这个吗”，店主会帮你。
Okay.
好的。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
And of course, if you have any questions or you want to comment on this lesson or any
当然，如果你有任何问题，或者想评论这节课或我们
of our lessons, you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
的任何课程，你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you all there.
我们希望能在那儿见到大家。
All right.
好了。
Bye.
再见。
Much surfing.
冲浪愉快。